
[
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Who was awarded the very first gold record?",
    "correct_answer": "Perry Como",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "The Beatles",
      "Elvis Presley",
      "Nat King Cole"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "What pop singer is known as 'The Material Girl'?",
    "correct_answer": "Madonna",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Christina Aguilera",
      "Taylor Swift",
      "Britney Spears"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "How much pressure do the strings in a grand piano exert on the frame?",
    "correct_answer": "30 Tons",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "3 Tons",
      "30 Lbs",
      "300 Lbs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "What is the oldest surviving musical instrument?",
    "correct_answer": "Flute",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Lyre",
      "Trumpet",
      "Drum"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "What singer holds the world record for most words in a hit single?",
    "correct_answer": "Eminem",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "50 Cent",
      "Kanye West",
      "Busta Rhymes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "What instrument is used by the indigenous people of Australia to accompany ceremonial dancing and singing?",
    "correct_answer": "Didgeridoo",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Yabahar",
      "Hydraulophone",
      "Zeusaphone"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "How many pieces of wood are there in a modern violin?",
    "correct_answer": "70",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "15",
      "2",
      "30"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "How many notes are included in a chromatic scale?",
    "correct_answer": "12",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "6",
      "5",
      "8"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "What is the longest running stage musical?",
    "correct_answer": "The Fantasticks",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Cats",
      "Phantom of the Opera",
      "Chicago"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Which of the following was NOT a founding member of the UK Music Hall of Fame?",
    "correct_answer": "David Bowie",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Madonna",
      "Elvis Presley",
      "Bob Marley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Music from the Renaissance period is grouped into two categories: Sacred music and Secular music.",
    "correct_answer": "True",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "What was the band known as Linkin Park originally called?",
    "correct_answer": "Xero",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Hybrid Theory",
      "Reanimators",
      "Meteora"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Which musical term means to play a piece of music lively and fast?",
    "correct_answer": "Allegro",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Cadenza",
      "Castrato",
      "Adagio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "The early music of the medieval church existed in the form of Gregorian chants. These chants are monophonic and instrumental.",
    "correct_answer": "False",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "True"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Ritornello is an unique feature of Baroque music is typically played on the harpsichord and doubled on the 'cello.",
    "correct_answer": "False",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "True"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "There are six music periods that are typically studied",
    "correct_answer": "True",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Which composer is not from the classical period?",
    "correct_answer": "Herbert Gronemeyer",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "W.A. Mozart",
      "Joseph Haydn",
      "J.C. Bach"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Christoph Gluck's 'O Del Nio Dolce Ardor' is an example of a(n)?",
    "correct_answer": "Aria",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Opera",
      "Cantata",
      "Libretto"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "boolean",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "Gregorian Chants was popular during medieval period.",
    "correct_answer": "True",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Music",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "easy",
    "question": "20th century rock music is influenced by these styles?",
    "correct_answer": "R&B and Country",
    "incorrect_answers": [
      "Jazz",
      "Gregorian and Plainchant",
      "It is not influenced by any styles"
    ]
  }
]
